

Prakash Rathod

Con. No.: 8140207928

prakash97rathod@gmail.com
243/3,
Sant Rohidas Nagar,
Thakkarbapa Nagar,
Ahmedabad
382350

➢ Soft Skills

- Solid Edge
- Auto Cad (2D & 3D)
- Basic Computer
- MS office

Language

- Gujarati
- Hindi
- English

> <u>Interests</u>

- Writing
- Music
- Social activity

Objective

To work in a firm with a professional work driven environment where I can utilize and apply my knowledge and skills which would enable me to grow as a design engineer while fulfilling organizational goals.

> Summary

Diploma Mechanical Engineer having 5 years of experience in various departments, especially in design engineering. Worked as supervisor in steel industry and working as a assistant design engineer in manufacturing industries. Having knowledge of various machine design software like AutoCAD and solid edge in 2D and 3D.

Education

•	S.S.C. (2012)	G.S.E.B.	First Class
•	Mechanical Draftsman (2014)	T.E.B.	First Class
•	Diploma Mechanical Eng. (2017)	G.T.U.	First Class

Experience

Ess	ar Steel India	Pvt. Ltd.	(07-2017 to 02-2018)
-----------------------	----------------	-----------	----------------------

- Diploma Trainee

• Bobbiler Text Machinery (04-2018 to 12-2018)

- Draftsman

• SL Engineers (12-2018 to 10-2020)

- Draftsman

• **Genest Engineers Pvt. Ltd.** (12-2020 to Present)

- Assistant Design Engineer

Work Description

- Having shop floor experience of continues casting process, and team management.
- Knowledge of machine elements and manufacturing processes.
- Working as an Ass. Design engineer. Designing machine elements economic as well as efficient.
- Dealing with design and manufacturing related problems.
- Strongly communicate with project engineers and purchase department.
- Making bill of materials and maintain all design documents for future reference.
- Working with Solid Edge 2020 version software, also knowledge of Auto Cad.
- Dealing with vendors and production department regarding technical issues.

Date: Prakash Rathod